What's up engineers? Indie Devdan here.
Today isn't just another agent coding
video. Let's get ahead of the curve with
a plan of our own because those who plan
the future tend to create it. Every plan
is a bet on the future. Every bet has
risks and rewards. The trick isn't
execution. It's choosing the right bets
in the first place. Today, I want to
share five big bets I'm personally
making for 2026 to stay ahead of the
curve. These bets point to where I'm
putting my agents, my time, my money,
and my compute. Some of these bets
you're going to expect, others will
surprise you. Take my plan for 2026 and
use it as a framework for your own road
map. Midway through, I'm going to reveal
a major announcement that ties it all
together. I'm so excited to finally
announce this, to finally release this.
It's built for engineers who know the
future of engineering is agent first.
Let's create the future with our plan
for engineering in 2026.
My first big bet is an easy one to make.
The ROI is clear and massively untapped.
Agents, but not just any agents. We're
talking about custom agents. If you're
working with just a single agent through
an agentic coding tool like clawed code
or the codec cli, you're ahead of the
majority of engineers. The 8020 of
software engineering can be summarized
in one word, agents. But if you're using
custom agents in your production
systems, I estimate you're immediately
in the top 1% of engineers. Why is that?
Why does that shoot you up so far? It's
because custom agents let you do scaled
nasty and I mean nasty in the literal
sense domain specific engineering work
in fractions of the time and complexity
that it used to take. When you encode
solutions into custom agents, you get
repeatable problem solving with compute.
So what are the risks here? Every plan
has bets. Every bet has risks and
rewards. Building effective agents,
shout out anthropic, takes time and
practice. Okay, the learning curve here
is steep and the over reliance on AI is
only going to increase. Okay, I don't
know about you, but I have constantly
increased my reliance on agents, on
agent coding tools, on language models.
This is how technology works. It gives
and it takes. What are the rewards here?
I think easily this puts you in the top
1% of engineering output. If you have
custom agents deployed into production,
you are going to outperform the rest of
the pack. Okay, this is the defining
competitive advantage in 2026, which is
why I'm betting big on custom agents.
I've built hundreds of crappy custom
agents, and guess what? In 2026, I'll be
building great custom agents and sharing
the journey. Make sure to like and
subscribe if you're not already a part
of the agentic journey.
Sometimes moving forward means leaving a
few things behind. We have to deprecate
our old engineering skills in 2026.
Okay, here's a helpful symbolic visual
you can use. All right, think of a
pencil and bear with me here. All right,
this is the perfectly balanced tool for
builders. You have creation at one end
and you have deletion at the other.
You're constantly drafting new skills
and erasing what no longer serve you.
Over time, though, both ends wear out
and you need to refresh and pick up a
new tool. You need to pick up a new
pencil. The pencil reminds us that
growth isn't just about writing the next
line, but also knowing when to erase and
start again. Okay? There are things
you're doing right now that you could
absolutely have your agent do for you.
The big kicker here in the age of agents
is that it's not about what you can do
anymore. So many engineers get this
wrong. It's not about you anymore. It's
not about your skills. It's about what
you can teach your agents to do. This is
a big big differentiating factor. we
talk about intact. More on that in just
a moment. We must deprecate the old ways
of engineering to make time, space, and
energy for the new ones. Now, of course,
the risks here are very obvious. We have
to break old multi-year, multi-deade
habits. This is going to be
uncomfortable and we are not going to
have potential skill atrophy. We are we
have guaranteed skill atrophy. Okay?
Think about the calculator. Think about
Google Maps. Think about any piece of
technology that you use that has
deprecated your ability to do the thing
the technology now does. This is
guaranteed in 2026. We are deprecating
our old skills. We are letting go of the
old ways so that we can introduce the
new ways. Okay? The productivity, the
gains, the future proofing of your
career, right? The future proofing of
your engineering career is going to be
massive when you just let go and stop
doing things the old way. I know for a
fact you might be one of these
engineers, okay? you know that agents
could do the work that you're about to
do, but you still do it the old way. You
still type line by line. You still copy
paste. You still, you know, write a
prompt that you know you could automate
in a reusable agentic workflow. You
know, you're doing things the slow way
because it's how you've always done
them. Let's let go. We have to deprecate
the old skills to make space and time
for the new ones.
If you're building valuable work with
agents, you've likely run into the two
constraints of agentic coding. My third
bet is to go big on limit breaking the
agentic coding constraints. What are the
constraints? You know what they are.
Planning and reviewing. We can now build
new plans and hand it off to our agents
at higher rates than ever. But us in the
planning process is what takes time. And
then of course at the end of the loop
when our agent has finished all the
work, what else takes the most time for
us? Reviewing. These are the constraints
of agentic coding. And in 2026, we're
going to blast through these. We're
going to limit break the agentic coding
constraints. And of course, the big
answer here I'm betting big on is custom
agents. All right. But not just custom
agents, right? It's custom agents inside
of ADWs, right? a pipeline of agents
that combines the old world of
engineering with the new world of
agents. Okay, this is the most powerful
abstraction that exists for engineers
right now. The ADW, more on that in a
moment. All right, in 2026, my plan is
to break through these constraints to
unlock insane scales. Now, this is going
to be hard. You know, none of these bets
just show up on your doorstep. This is
going to take effort from both you and
I. The implementation here is complex.
That upfront investment is going to
cost. This is where we lose all the vibe
coders, right? You have to have a deep
understanding of your codebase to really
increase your planning and your
reviewing velocity. You cannot teach
something to do something that you do
not know how to do. Okay, this is just
reality. If you want to push agents to
their limits, you must know what you're
trying to teach them to do, right? And
of course, the rewards here are huge. I
estimate there's a 1 to two order of
magnitude improvement lying at the other
end lying at the end of the cave if we
can limit break the planning and
reviewing constraints of agentic coding.
I said this back in 2023 24 and it's
still true now. The chat interface is
the laziest and most overused interface
for agents. Okay, in 2026, I'm investing
a ton of time into multi-agent UIs and I
eyes, interaction interfaces. Okay,
specifically, we're talking about voice.
The whole point here is to increase the
information rate between you and your
agents. Okay, you want to be getting
more work done faster, commanding more
compute with multi- aent UIs and faster
interaction interfaces, right?
Specifically, again, voice. This lets us
wield more compute faster than ever. If
you could communicate everything in your
head right now to a multi- aent system
that can do the work for you, wouldn't
that be amazing? Right? Wouldn't that
quite literally change your future?
Okay, these systems are right around the
corner. You and I can build these right
now. What are the trade-offs here?
Right? I think this is going to be hard.
Okay, I I have an idea of what, you
know, several versions of this look
like. previous couple weeks video, we've
been talking about and pushing into
custom agent UIs. I'm mostly concerned
here about user confusion, right? What
are users and customers going to think
about this? Because putting multiple
agents into a single UI and
orchestrating all that feedback, all
that logging, all the important bits of
information is challenging. This is a
complex UI UX design challenge as well.
You know, all the designers out there
who tune in, all the builder designers,
uh it's your time to shine. All right.
So, of course, the betsense here are of
course massive. I mean, there's a reason
I'm betting on these things, right?
Between all these bets, we're going to
see a probably another ma order of
magnitude um increase in engineering
output with the right multi- aent
system. Okay? And to be clear, I'm
talking about use case specific multi-
aent systems, multi- aent UIs. I'm not
talking about another, you know, claude
code wrapper. I'm not talking about
another background task manager for your
agent CLI. I'm talking about your
product, getting the UI to have many
agents operate on it and get more work
done faster than ever. Okay? Everyone's
going way too wide. It's time to focus.
It's time to go deep. It's time to solve
real engineering problems with this
incredible technology.
Final bet. We are going to max out our
compute. We are going to be compute
maxing. Let me tell you a secret.
However much compute you think you're
using, however great you think you are
at agentic coding, you're not using that
much compute and you're not that great.
Okay, I know it sounds a little intense,
a little aggressive, but what makes me
say that? It's because unless you have
an always on 24/7 agent solving problems
for you on your behalf all the time, you
can and should be using more compute.
Okay, compute maxing will be a major
focus of mine in 2026 and I highly
recommend it for you as well. Always be
thinking, how can I use more compute?
And the answer isn't you jump from
prompting back and forth with cloud code
to all of a sudden you build a 24-hour,
you know, 7 days a week agent. That's
not how this works, okay? We're
engineers. We operate in the gray and
the messy and the progression of it all.
We always want to be thinking, how can I
use more compute today? And and I think
about this all the time. I am no
exception here. As much compute as I
use, um I know for a fact it's not
nearly as much as I know it can be.
Think about all the developer workflows
you have. Think about all the products,
tools, and applications that are
untouched by valuable language models,
prompt chains, all the way up to agents.
There's so much potential and we're here
to unlock it. In 2026, I'm going to
build my first always on custom agent
and I'm going to share the journey with
you right here on the channel. There are
big risks here though, right? Very
obviously this is going to cost us quite
a bit. Okay, but we are betting on the
fact we also have a side bet that you
know the cost of compute will continue
to decline and we'll continue to get
great open-source lowcost high
intelligent models like the huge Quinn
series that was just released, right?
These are these are groundbreaking
models that are getting smaller and
better that we're going to be able to
operate on with. Okay, but still, you
know, operating 24/7 doing real
engineering work. This is going to cost.
There's going to be architecture and
infrastructure complexity and we're
probably going to end up wasting a lot
of compute to get there, right? But this
is how it works. Okay, you need to put
the reps in to even know what's
possible. And this is a big idea we talk
about in the advanced lessons in TAC.
Almost there. We're almost at the
reveal. Give me one more second here. Of
course, the reward here is absolutely
massive. If you're compute maxing, you
have living software that works for you
while you sleep. And by the way, this
has been the mission for this channel. I
know a lot of, you know, recent
subscribers, you think we just come on
here and we talk about the latest cloud
code release, but we focus on it because
it's the best tool for the job because
it helps us move closer to the mission
of the Andy Devdan channel. Build living
software that works for us while we
sleep. Okay. And this gets us closer to
that goal. I finally have an
architecture that I think can provide
some solid value. I'm going to be
building this out in 2026 and sharing
the journey. This is true agentic
automation and true exponential
leverage, right? Imagine this thing
always on. And by the way, you know, we
just had that release coming out from
OpenAI with their new chat GPT pulse.
The subline here is great. Now chat GPT
can start the conversation. On the
channel, there's a video we put out a
long time ago now, but it was called the
two-way prompt. And it was a prediction.
It was kind of a bet that at some point
these systems will become so powerful
that they will start prompting us. And
so it's interesting to see chat GPT
pulse kind of moving down that that
direction. Kind of a combination of a a
scheduling system, but also ChatGpt is
learning more and more about you and I
so it can solve your problems and ask
you for the next step, right? But this
is that same idea, right? Open AAI is
pushing toward compute maxing. That's
what this is, right? If you have an
always on system building for you in the
background 247 you are going to
outperform in a massive massive way at
some point the conversation will flip
and our agents will prompt us more than
we prompt them. In 2026 we will be
compute maxing. Okay so five big bets
and it all leads up to something
incredible. So we have custom agents
deprecating old skills. We're letting go
of the past so we can accept the future.
limit break the agentic coding
constraints. We want to increase our
planning and our review velocity to
unlock the next order of magnitude
improvement. We're talking about multi-
aent user interfaces and interaction
interfaces. This is a big bet I'm
already making right now. And of course,
compute maxing. To scale your impact,
you scale your compute. Okay, this is
the equation to win for engineering in
2025 and beyond. The agent architecture
has changed everything. And that leads
us to a massive opportunity that I'm
beyond excited to share with you right
now. It's finally here. I am actively
investing in all these bets and I have
some results already that I want to
share with you. Let's take our bets and
put them into raw day-to-day actions,
raw tactics that we can use on a daily
basis. Allow me to introduce
tactical agentic coding.
Here you can master the tactics of
agenta coding to scale far beyond AI
coding and vibe coding with advanced
engineering so powerful that your
codebase runs itself. This is the phase
2 agentic coding course built for
engineers in the AI age. I have been
working 996 around the clock to get this
ready and to get this shipped to get
this in a great state for you for
engineers that know that the future is a
dentic. The future is agent first. And
by the way, if you don't like being sold
things or if you think I'm an AI grifter
or whatever the case is, it's time for
you to tune out. Okay, so what is
tactical agentic coding? This is for
engineers that ship and we're taking
things further. We know for a fact that
AI coding is not enough. And there are a
bunch of big ideas that engineers are
missing right now that you can get ahead
of with tactical agent coding. Okay, AI
coding was just the beginning. VIP
coding is the lowest hanging fruit and
95 probably 99% of all code bases are
now outdated and inefficient. Important
time to focus. You the engineer are the
bottleneck, not the models, not the
tools, not the agents. That post about
what the best agent decoding tool is,
what the best model is, the best
pricing, all of that is irrelevant.
Everyone is missing the big picture. We
are the bottlenecks now. It's a skill
issue. There is a new engineering role
that has emerged. I've been waiting for
this. I've been betting on this and it's
finally here. You and I can now become
agentic engineers. This isn't about
models, prompts, or agents. It's about
composing the old world of software
engineering with the new world of agents
to achieve exponential scales of
engineering. Allow me to just pitch
this. This might get a little salesy,
but the key ideas here are too important
to just drive by. Okay? You know, in
tactical agent coding, we are going to
transition into this new role of
engineering. You'll think hard to step
out the loop, and we're going to ask one
simple guiding question throughout this
course. What if your codebase could ship
itself?
This is not for beginners. If you're not
shipping to production, if you're not a
mid to senior level engineer, if you're
not shipping with agent coding tools,
this is not for you. Okay? So, what are
you going to learn here? My mission is
to transform you into an engineer they
can't replace. How are we going to do
that? It's a crazy goal, right? That
sounds wild. They can't replace. We do
this with two concrete actions. Just
like with our big bets, right? I've
already started placing these bets and
putting them into action. These bets are
already inside tactical agentic coding.
We're going to do two things. Let go of
the old ways of engineering and master
the new best tool for the job. By
internalizing the eight tactics of
agentic coding, you're going to become
an engineer that builds the system that
builds the system. It's not about what
we can do anymore. It's about what we
can teach our agents to do. We are
building the system that builds the
system. There will be an engineer on
your team, hopefully it's you, that will
be orchestrating fleets of agents inside
the agentic system that handles all the
application work you're wasting your
time doing. Okay, this is just the
reality. Okay, you know, forgive me for
being a little harsh here, but um I am
always I always try to show up here
every Monday to deliver concrete raw,
you know, engineering truths and
realities. And this is one of them,
okay? And you've seen some of this. If
you're using agents, you know this. If
you're still watching this video, you
know this is true. Agents are how you
win the game of engineering in 2025 and
beyond. So, there's more information
here. Check this out. But the structure
here is a little bit different. Okay, so
I could not fit everything I needed to
in tactical agentic coding. So I created
a gentic horizon. These are extended
lessons you can upgrade to if you're
interested. The key lessons, the key
ideas are in tactical agenda coding. But
if you want more and if you want some
extra bonuses, check out Agenta Horizon.
Okay, here you'll get three lessons
right now that we've been teasing over
the past 3 weeks and you'll get three
future lessons that you get to vote on.
This is a new voting mechanism. You get
to vote on exactly what you want to see
next. Okay, tactical coding follows a
similar formula. If you've taken
principal a coding, you're familiar with
this. We have eight lessons and eight
tactics. Okay, we're going from beginner
to intermediate to advanced. All right.
Now, if the course is a good fit for
you, lesson one is going to feel like a
bit of a waste of time. It's going to
feel a little bit slow, but lesson one
is critically important. This is where
we set the stage for everything else. If
you build the fundamentals right, if you
build that groundwork, right, everything
else falls into place. We only have two
beginner lessons here. Things move up
very quickly to the intermediate level.
We talk about turning your prompts into
plans and your plans into something
brand new, a next generation agentic
prompting technique you can use. We talk
about that in lesson three. And then
things go bananas from there. Okay, AFK
agents close the loops, right? Scale
your compute to get more confidence.
Build self-correcting systems. Destroy
those bugs. Destroy those
hallucinations. And then things go
parabolic in the advanced lessons. Let
your agent focus. We have agentic review
and documentation. We have a big secret
reveal in lesson 7. And then the one big
idea to rule them all, the agentic
layer. So that's the lesson structure.
And then of course, as mentioned, you
have the agentic horizon extended
lessons if you're interested. This is an
additional upgrade you can buy if you
want to push it even further. All right,
so we're back for phase two. And I just
want to say, you know, I want to stop
for a moment. Uh, none of this is
possible without the, you know, kind
words and the involvement and the
participation of you, the engineer, and
thousands, you know, literally hundreds
of thousands of other engineers now who
have watched, who have shared their kind
words. Uh, we've come a long way since
the GBT 3.5 and Ader days, but here we
are. Um, and now it's time to take it to
the next next step. So, you know, a
bunch of kind words here from everyone.
Big shout out to you guys. And then we
have uh the final pricing. It's super
important to touch on this. I have two
deals running right now. Of course, I
always like to do an early bird special
and then if you're a principal AI coding
member, this cuts the price in half. If
you're not a principal a coding member,
don't worry. You still get the early
bird special. By the time you're seeing
this, you'll probably have 16 days here
and maybe 30 here. I'm not sure. So,
take advantage of this. This is not a
marketing trick or anything. I just want
to reward engineers who move fast and
invest in themselves. All right? There
are tons of bonuses in here. Feel free
to check this out step by step. If
you're an individual, you can purchase
Agentic Horizon after you buy Tactical
Agent Coding. I'll show you what that
looks like in just a second. And if
you're purchasing for a team, you can
click team right here and add as many
seats as you need. As you add seats,
you're going to see your discount go up.
Since we don't have an early bird or
pack discount for team purchases, we are
applying that discount to a Genta
Horizon extended lessons. You get a
major discount on both of these lesson
sets. If you're interested, you can
scale this up and uplevel your
engineering org. So, there's a ton of
value in here. Uh, if you're not sure if
this is for you, check the FAQ. Watch
this to qualify. This is for mid to
senior level engineers that know agents
are the future of engineering. Okay,
this is going to be hard. This is not a
simple course. We cover advanced topics.
You need to know about agents. You need
to know about the big three context
model prompt. And, you know, by the way,
just to mention this, this is completely
risk-free. We have a no questions asked
30-day refund before you start lesson 4.
So, if you get to lesson three and you
don't like my style, you don't like the
ideas, you don't like the vision, no
problem. No hard feelings. I'll get you
a full refund before you start lesson 4
before you upgrade to Aentic Horizon.
You get everything back. Okay? I want
the right engineers in this course. If
that's not you, no problem at all. So,
this makes it completely risk-f free.
You can just jump in here and get
started. Okay? If you're a pack member,
be sure to sign into the right account
before you purchase. Once you click
master agent coding, you'll be taken to
the landing page of the course and it
looks just like this. You'll have
premium access to tactical agent coding
where we start with the first two
lessons. Every next lesson unlocks when
you complete 50% of the previous lesson.
And if you scroll down here, you can see
agentic horizon. Here I have it
unlocked. I can vote on the next lessons
and I can freely watch any one of these
lessons as I choose. All right, so this
is what the lesson page looks like and
this is all here waiting for you. This
is tactical agent coding. All right, now
super long pitch. I know there are a lot
of engineers that have been waiting for
this. So I just want to be really
thorough with the announcement here. I
want to say huge thank you to all the
engineers that have been excited and
patient for this release. This course is
the result of feedback from hundreds of
engineers. It's a massive edge. you have
the opportunity to gain right now. Okay,
this is for engineers that ship. We are
not vibe coding here. AI coding is not
enough. We're not prompting and not
looking. We're going deep and we're
using this technology to extend what we
can do as engineers. The whole purpose
here, again, my goal here is to turn you
into an engineer they can't replace. So,
huge edge. Get in here ASAP. Take
advantage of the early bird and pack
deal. They will expire. I want to reward
engineers who move fast and invest in
themselves. These deals will expire and
the price will go up to the full price.
By the way, if you're looking at this
price right without pack membership or
without the early bird and you think
it's a shocking price, it probably means
it's not for you. Okay? This for mid to
senior level engineers shipping to
production and they know that agents are
what's next and they want to win. Get in
here, get your next generation
perspective on how to build better and
faster with agents. No matter what you
do, focus on your plan for the future.
Even if you aren't interested in TAC,
make sure you have a plan for yourself
for the future. All right, I'm betting
on custom agents. I'm letting go of old
skills. I'm limit breaking the review
and the planning constraints of agent
coding. And then we're going to dive
hard and fast into multi- aent UIs to
use more compute than ever. And then of
course, it all kind of sums up to
compute maxing. Whatever you're doing
right now, however much compute you're
using, you're not using enough. I have a
huge prediction in 2026. We're going to
see our first compute crunch. We will
have a limited supply of compute. We're
already starting to see signs of that.
All right. But as you and I, you know,
the engineers kind of on the bleeding
edge as we start scaling up our compute
more and more, this will become a larger
and larger problem. The more compute you
can use, the more you realize you can
do, which leads you to using more
compute. So, this is my plan for 2026.
you now have a massive opportunity
available to you. Check out Tactical
Agentic Coding. We're going to be
breaking this down and touching on this
in the future on the channel. No matter
what you do here, stay focused and keep
building.